Jan Oliver Waldeck

jan.waldeck@gmail.com Portfolio: www.jwaldeck.com • LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/jwaldeck

CREATIVE DIRECTOR WITH FOCUS ON UX/UI

12-year design and creative career spanning mostly across multimedia and web projects. Hands-on experience conceiving and delivering innovation, blending practicality and exceptional user oriented design with a steady focus on business results, deadlines and profitability/budget.

Strong believer in the importance and knowledge about user personas, buying journeys and UX Experience Maps, drafting designs, sitemaps and high level functionality based on user behavior and expectations.

- Cross platform Creative and Art Direction
- Team Management
- Interactive Design and Front-End development
- UX/UI and Prototyping (Axure and MarvelApp)
- Campaigns and Brand conception
- Familiar with Wordpress, CMS Made Simple, Joomla and Processwire CMS's
- Entrepreneurial Initiatives
- Self Motivated and Excellent Communication skills

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AllWebCafe (www.allwebcafe.com) – Berwyn, PA
Director of Innovation & Experience (Creative Director)

Sep 2013 - Current

- Leads the creative team and is responsible for driving the creative process as it relates to both user experience and design for online and offline initiatives.
- Led a major re-branding of a multi million company in the insurance industry. Rebrand included: New identity system, a new responsive website and a wide variety of marketing materials.
- Drives the UX process for architecture and design of responsive websites and digital campaigns and is responsible for managing multiple projects from concept through completion.
- · Fosters communication and collaboration within the creative team and across departments and peers.
- · Identifies areas of departmental, strategic and personal improvements and implements them accordingly.

QVC (www.qvc.com) – West Chester, PA Managing Multimedia Designer

June 2012 - Sep 2013

- Led the team and an external agency on design, development and implementation of the new QVC iPad app launch July 2013.
- · Provided art direction and guidance guided towards mobile platforms for multiple creative areas of the business.
- Maintained strong working relationships with creative directors ensuring the vision is executed properly and on point with brand and creative guidelines.
- Conducted thoughtful and deep analysis on responsive website and second screen opportunities and drive recommendations for the best creative strategy for QVC.
- Focused on designing new platforms and mobile experiences that bridge the brand to customer experience through Interactive Campaigns, Social TV and Second Screen Initiatives.
- Led cross-functional developer and business teams to ensure that design and usability best practices were carried out and business goals were met.

THE BROWNSTEIN GROUP (www. brownsteingroup.com) - Philadelphia, PA Interactive Design Freelancer

2011 - 2012

- Led the creative concept and design of several IKEA digital peak week campaigns.
- Created the concept and design of IKEA's "Fix This Kitchen" website a microsite for a reality TV show.

Jan Oliver Waldeck Page 2 of 2

DOCTYPEMEDIA, LLC (www.doctypemedia.com) - Durham, NC / Philadelphia, PA Project Manager, Front-End Developer and Designer

2009 - Current

- Founded a consulting business and web development agency to assist small and medium companies to create customized
 online solutions, institutional websites and achieve best SEO practices.
- Managed front-end, user interface at clipik.com, a San Francisco based video editing crowd source startup.
- Provided clients user interfaces and easy to use backend systems built on innovative and contemporary website layouts, increasing their brand's web awareness.
- · Partnered with international clients on iPad and iPhone design and development projects.
- Successfully designed, launched and managed the corporate web presence of more than 10 small and medium businesses within 15 months.

FREELANCER (www.jwaldeck.com) - São Paulo, BRAZIL Consultant, Front-End Developer and Art Director

2007 - 2009

• Designed and implemented online projects, created user interfaces and applied open source PHP content management systems to websites for more than 25 clients in both non-profit and corporate organizations. Websites implemented with strong SEO efforts, increasing the volume of traffic and rankings in Google's Organic Search.

CREDIT SUISSE HEDGING-GRIFFO ASSET MANAGEMENT - São Paulo, Brazil

2003 - 2007

Online Marketing Coordinator and Web Designer (2004 – 2007)

- Performed in-depth analysis of visitor trends, website functionality and navigation to recommend marketing opportunities. Aligned recommendations with multi-functional teams and Internet agencies.
- Developed a standardized online communication process and implemented an in-house newsletter tool to facilitate the
 relationship with clients and to understand the metrics and interest generated with each communication. An average of
 30.000 e-mails were sent each month to clients and partners through the new tool.
- Created and introduced a database of competitor websites to gain information on visitor trends, defined target markets, measure marketing opportunities and maintained overall positioning.

Marketing Analyst (2003 – 2004)

- Developed new marketing materials for the sales team, from brainstorming with the team to providing the final prints.
- Responsible for developing internal marketing strategies with the HR team to enhance the corporate communication strategies among employees.
- Selected to join the online marketing department within 12 months.

AGENCIA CLICK - São Paulo, Brazil

2002 - 2003

Project Management Assistant

- Managed a cross-functional project team for a major national cosmetic retail client with a \$500K annual budget
- · Created and organized project timelines and methods of controlling risk management and budgets.

EDUCATION / SKILLS

2013 to Present: Treehouse/Lynda.com - Self-paced online training to keep abreast with modern programming and UX/UI best

practices.

2012: QVC University – Leadership Training towards becoming an effective manager 1999 – 2002: Bachelor of Social Communication (Marketing), Dec 2002 - ESPM, São Paulo, Brazil

- Fluent in English and Portuguese and elementary proficiency in German and French.
- Continued education through Lynda.com, an online specialization platform (Adobe CC, SEO, PHP, PM, UX/UI)
- Proficient in Office, Online Project Management (ActiveCollab, Basecamp and Track), Adobe CC Suite, basic CSS and HTML, Axure, MarvelApp
- Advanced knowledge of Open Source CMS systems such as Joomla, Processwire and Wordpress
- Portfolio of work: www.jwaldeck.com